Hilda Mason, City Council 029
People's Archive, MLK Library
Hilda Mason, City Council Records
1970-1998
People's Archive, MLK Library
029
147.5 Linear feet
Hilda Mason was a city council member from 1977 to 1997. She championed the causes of home rule and children's education and welfare, among others. The City Council records consist of budget documents, financial records, Board of Education and Committee on Education records, files on the University of the Distric of Columbia, files on capital improvements, and legislative documents among other items.
Biographical / Historical
Hilda Howland Mae Mason was born in Altavista, (Lynch Station, Virginia) on June 4, 1916. She attended Virginia Seminary in Lynchburg and St. Paul's College in Lawrenceville. Mason relocated to Washington, DC in 1945. She later enrolled at Miners Teachers College and earned her undergraduate degree in 1952. She was a teacher, counselor and administrator in the DC public school system for 19 years, until she was elected to the Board of Education from Ward 4. She served from 1972-1977, after which she was appointed to complete the term of Julius Hobson, Sr., the at-Large member of the DC City Council. After completing Hobson's term, she won an at-Large seat on her own merit. Mason was a champion of education in DC as chair of the Council's Education, Libraries and Recreation Committee (1981-1997), the Local, Regional and Federal Affairs Committee, the Human Services Committee, and the Judiciary Committee. To date, her tenure on the City Council remains the longest term of service in the city's history. Mason was also a steadfast member of the DC Statehood Party, as well as a supporter of the development of the University of the District of Columbia. The law school library bears her name and the name of her husband, Charles N. Mason, Jr., a graduate of Harvard University and Howard University Law School.
Custodial History
Hilda Mason donated her collection of City Council materials to DC Public Library Special Collections in March 1997.
Scope and Contents
The Hilda Mason City Council Records document Mason's deep involvement with D.C. politics and community life. Among the records are documents of her time on the Education, Libraries, and Recreation Committee, the Human Services Committee, and the Judiciary Committee. The records consist of budget documents, financial records, Board of Education and Committee on Education records, files on the University of the Distric of Columbia, files on capital improvements, and legislative documents among other items.
African Americans; Black persons; Women; Politics and government; District of Columbia. City Council
- Series 1
  - Aid to Families with Dependent Children, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Airports, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control Act, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alley Closing (1 of 3), 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alley Closing (2 of 3), 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alley Closing (3 of 3), 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Deficiency Act, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Appropriation Act, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Appropriation Act, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Appropriation Act, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Appropriation Act, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Appropriation Accounts, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Appropriation Act, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Appropriation Act (1 of 2), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Appropriation Act (2 of 2), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Appropriation Act (1 of 2), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Appropriation Act (2 of 2), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Appropriation Act, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Appropriation Act (1 of 4), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Appropriation Act (2 of 4), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Appropriation Act (3 of 4), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Appropriation Act (4 of 4), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Appropriations (1 of 2), 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Appropriations (2 of 2), 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Appropriation, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Appropriation, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Appropriation, 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Appropriation (1 of 2), 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Appropriation (2 of 2), 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Appropriations (1 of 2), 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Appropriations (2 of 2), 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Appropriations (1 of 2), 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Appropriations (2 of 2), 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Appropriations, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Architectural Barriers, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Asbestos, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Maureen W. Ayton, 1981-1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - BAL Amendments of 1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bankruptcy, 1978-2001 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Barney Circle, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Barney Circle Freeway, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Bill 4, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Board of Ed, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Boiling V Sharpe, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bottle Legislation, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Burg, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Cable Television, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - California Recusal Case, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Capital Improvements Program, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Capital Project Borrowing, 1946-1983 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Capital Project Borrowing, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Census Redistricting, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Census Redistricting, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Chanceries Legislation, 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Chanceries, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Chanceries, 1985-1988 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Compulsory Motor Vehicle, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Compulsory Motor Vehicle, 1971-1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Eaton Program, 1979-1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Census and Ward, 1980-1984 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Census and Ward, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Census and Ward, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Census Figures, 1976-1985 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Census Figures, 1960-1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Chadha, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Chadha, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Chadha, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Chanceries Legislation, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Chanceries Legislation, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Census Redistricting, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Census Redistricting, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Jill Kerr Conway, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Convention CTR-Labor Rel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Anna J. Cooper Resolution, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Cooperative Housing, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Court Orders - DC, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Cozzi, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Curfew, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Curfew, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Bd. Of Education Budget FY 1983, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Bd. Of Education Budget FY 1983, 1981-1983 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - FY 1983 Budget Education Hearing, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Budget Supp'l FY 1982 Education (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Education, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Bd. Of Education Budget, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Board of Education Budget FY 1982 (1 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Board of Education Budget FY 1982 (2 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Board of Education Budget FY 1982 (3 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Board of Education Budget FY 1982 (4 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Education Appropriation Correspondence (1 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Education Appropriation Correspondence (2 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Board of Ed: Arnold and Porter Opinion, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Board of Education Audit Report, 1980-1983 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Education - Board Vacancy W.I, 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Education Committee (Miscellaneous), 1981 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Education Budget Letter, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Education Budget FY 1986, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - FY 1985 Supply Budget. Hearing Education Ctee. 5-24-85 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Educ. Budget FY 1984 (1 of 4), 1983 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Educ. Budget FY 1984 (2 of 4), 1983 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Educ. Budget FY 1984 (3 of 4), 1983 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Educ. Budget FY 1984 (4 of 4), 1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Education Budget FY 1983 (1 of 3), 1981 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Education Budget FY 1983 (2 of 3), 1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Education Budget FY 1983 (3 of 3), 1981 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Education Budget FY 1982, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Bd. Of Education Meetings, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Education Board President Election, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Education Budget FY 1985, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Education FY 1985 Budget Hearing 4/14/84, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Education Ctee May 31 1958 Supp. Budget FY 1985 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Education Budget - McKinney, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Charter Amdt. Gen'l Obligation Bonds Kane and Mason, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - City of Washington, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Civilian Complaint Review Bd. Bill 3-247 (1 of 2), 1980 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Civilian Complaint Review Bd. Bill 3-247 (2 of 2), 1980 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - David A. Clarke, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - COG - Water Resources Planning, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Alwyut. Cohall, 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Commercial and Apt. Property Values, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Commissioners of DC, 1878 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Committee on the District of Columbia- Bill Before Congress, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Compensation Policies Hearing - Committee on the Whole Public Hearing on "Compensation policies for employees of the District of Columbia Government" Council Member Mason, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Congressional Layover - Resolutions of Disapproval etc., 1981 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Law School Memo, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Congressional Miscellaneous (1 of 3), 1979-1981 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Congressional Miscellaneous (2 of 3), 1979-1981 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Congressional Miscellaneous (3 of 3), 1979-1981 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Daylight Saving Time, 1984-1987 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - D.C Register, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Daughter of the American Revolution, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Dishonored Checks, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Displaced Employee Program, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Brian Doherty, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Doors - Locked, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Double Dipping, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Thomas M. Downs, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Draft Registration, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Driver Education, 1980-1989 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Education CTEE 10/5/1983 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Education CTEE 9/26/83, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Education CTEE 9/13/83, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Education CTEE 7-11-83, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Education CTEE 6/27/83, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Ed. CTEE June 13 1983 Endowment -INV Portfolio (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Education CTEE May 23 1983 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Education CTEE 4/25/83, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Education CTEE March 14 1983 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Education CTEE Feb. 28 1983 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Education CTEE 1/21/1983 FY 1984 Budget Hearing (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Education CTEE No. 10 1982 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Education CTEE 10/13/82, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Education CTEE 9/29/82, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Education CTEE 7/28/82, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Committee on Education June 23 1982 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Committee on Ed 5/26/82, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Education CTEE 5/12/82, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Education CTEE 4-28-82, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Education CTEE 4-22-82 Budget Mark up RY 82 Supplemental, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Education CTEE 3-24-82, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Education CTEE - 1981 Sur Budge Hearing Markup (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Education Expenditures, 1975-1978 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Education Capital Budget, 1982-1984 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Education Expenditures 1 of 3, 1975-1978 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Education Expenditures 2 of 3, 1975-1978 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Education Expenditures 3 of 3, 1975-1978 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Education - Meeting December 10 1934 Room 114 Charles M. Mason Jr., 1984 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Education - Meeting November 26 1984 Room 114 Charles M. Mason Jr. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Education CIEE 10/22/1984 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Education CIEE 9/24/84 Asbestos, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Education Ctee 6/11/84, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Education CTEE 5/29/84, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Education CTEE Roundtable School Health 4/9/84, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Education CTEE 12/5/83, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Education CTEE Hearing 12/5/83, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Education CTEE 11/14/83, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Committee on Education Regular Meeting Wednesday March 10 1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Ed. Committee Meeting Feb. 24 '82, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Ed. Committee Meeting Feb. 5 1982 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Ed. Committee Meeting Jan. 13 1982 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Ed. CTEE 11/25/81 Mt. Vernon, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Education CTEE Oct. 28 1981 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Education CTEE Oct. 14 1981 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Early Out Retirement, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Education CTEE Sept. 30 1981 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Education CTEE June 24 1981 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Education CTEE Meeting 6/10/81, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Education CTEE Meeting 5/27/81, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Education CTEE May 13 1981 Meeting (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Hearing Education Committee May 1 1981 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Education Committee 4/29/81, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Education CTEE 4/8/81, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - COMM on ED. 3/25/81 BD. Of ED., 1981 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - ED. Comm 3/11/81, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Education CTEE 2/11/81, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Education Committee Rules, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Education Contracting, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Education- Contingency Fund School Space, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Education- "Distinct Education", 1983 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Education Federal Grants, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Education- Finance CTEE, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Education Finance Commission, 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Education- Food Service, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Education General, 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Education- Hobson v Hanson, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Education J. Ford, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Education - Impact Aid and Indirect Cost, 1981-1982 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Educational Licensure, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Lockridge Report, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Education - Mayors CTEE, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Dedication- Montgomery County, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Education - Motor Pool, 1983-1984 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Education: Parents United for Full Public School Fundraising 1 of 2, 1982-1986 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Education: Parents United for Full Public School Fundraising 2 of 2, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Education - School Nurses, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Education Pay Raises Etc. 1 of 3, 1981-1982 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Education Pay Raises Etc. 2 of 3, 1981-1982 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Education Pay Raises etc. 3 of 3, 1981-1982 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Education - Miscellaneous 1 of 3, 1981-1985 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Education - Miscellaneous 2 of 3, 1981-1985 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Education- Miscellaneous 3 of 3, 1981-1985 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Education CTEE 10/16/85 Pay Raises, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Education Policy AMD' MTS Act of 1980 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Education and Privacy Rights Act, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Education Residency, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Board WTG July '85, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Minnesota Av. July '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Budget CTTE. July '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Safety/Special Projects/Pensions and Operations, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Operations Committee Meeting June 1985 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Awards Program June '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Air Quality and Noise Analysis-Wheaton July '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Min Affairs Subtle June '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Planning and Admin. Cite June '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Board Mtg. June ' 85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Budget CTTE. May '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Minority Affairs May '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Planning and Admin Ctte. May '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Planning and Admin April '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Minor Affairs CTEE. April '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Farecard Procurement April '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - JCC Committee Jan. '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Budget CTTEE Jan '85, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Small Bus Material Aug. '84, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Compensation and Benefits Info Jan '85, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Metrorail Reliability May '85, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Hearing - E Route, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Board of Education - Residence Bilingual Psychologist, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Education B.D Com. On Rules Etc., 1981 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Board of Education Student Membership Report 1 of 2, 1982-1987 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Board of Education Student Membership Report 2 of 2, 1982-1987 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Education - Swimming Pools, 1982-1987 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Education Task Force, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Staff Reports July '85, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Special Board Meeting 7/3/85, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Planning and Administration May '85, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Education Tax Credit, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Education [Trespassing on School Property BILL 5-556], 1984 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Board of Elections and Ethics 1 of 3, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Board of Elections and Ethics 2 of 3, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Board of Elections and Ethics 3 of 3, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Board of Elections and Ethics 1 of 4, 1988-1992 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Board of Elections and Ethics 2 of 4, 1988-1992 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Board of Elections and Ethics 3 of 4, 1988-1992 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Board of Elections and Ethics 4 of 4, 1988-1992 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Elections - General 1 of 4, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Elections - General 2 of 4, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Elections - General 3 of 4, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Elections - General 4 of 4, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Elections Residence - Dunn V Blumstein Etc. 405- V533, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Elections and Board of Legislation, 1981-1983 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Election- Ethics Board Vacancies, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Elections and Ethics - Conflict of Interest investigation, 1980-1982 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Elections - 1981 investigation 1 of 2, 1981-1984 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Elections - 1981 investigation 2 of 2, 1981-1984 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Elections - Initiatives, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Election Act Amendment. DC Law 4-88, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Board of Elections andEthics Campaign Finance 1 of 3, 1979-1984 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Board of Elections andEthics Campaign Finance 2 of 3, 1979-1984 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Board of Elections andEthics Campaign Finance 3 of 3, 1979-1984 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Elections - Dunn v. Blumstein Etc., 1972 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Elections - Initiatives - Finance, 1979-1982 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Electoral College, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Emergency Legislation (Wash. Home Ownership Council v D.C, 1979-1984 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Evans v Cornman, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Families with Children Equal Rights Bill 3-74, 1979-1982 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Financial MGT. Task Force, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Financial Reports, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Fire Dep't - Mutual Aid, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - James R. Forman, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Freedom of Information, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - B.B French School - Capital Hill Arts Workshop, undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Furlough - Pocket Veto, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Gallaudet College, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - French v. Devine Hatch Act 1 of 3 (1982) (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - French v. Devine Hatch Act 2 of 3 (1982) (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - French v. Devine Hatch Act 3 of 3 (1982) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - US General Accounting Office Comptroller General 1 of 4, 1978-1986 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - US General Accounting Office Comptroller General 2 of 4, 1978-1986 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - US General Accounting Office Comptroller General 3 of 4, 1978-1986 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - US General Accounting Office Comptroller General 4 of 4, 1978-1986 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Georgetown Univ. Rev. Bonds, 1981-1990 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Glover- Archibald Park, 1966-1987 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Georgetown Waterfront, 1984-1985 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Hatch Act (Statehood and Independence) 1 of 2, 1981-1985 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Hatch Act (Statehood and Independence) 2 of 2, 1981-1985 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Healing Arts, 1979-1980 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Archie Hobson Statehood Article, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Honorable and Reverend, 1873-1979 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Housing Finance Agency Bonds, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Norma Hobson, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Immigration and NAT., 1979-1983 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Inaugural Regulations, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Income Tax - Lottery Prizes Bills 4-510 and 5 -65, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Income Tax Conformity Bill, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Piggy-Back Income Tax 1981, 1980-1981 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Interest Rate - USURY, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Initiatives # 3 and #6 Counts, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Jesse Jackson, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - King Birthday Holiday, 1982-1984 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Judicial System of D.C Autonomy 1 of 2, 1979-1984 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Judicial System of D.C Autonomy 2 of 2, 1979-1984 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - James B. Lancaster, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Land Grant Colleges, 1961-1962 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Landlord - Tenant, 1977-1979 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Landsburgh Building, 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Lead Paint Elimination, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Legal News Digest, 1983-1985 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Legislative Summaries, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Library Public, 1985-1990 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Litigation General, 1982-1983 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Marijuana Initiative #4, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Hector Marquin, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - May Day Judgement Creditors, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Metropolitan A.M.E Church, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Floretta McKenzie, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Lawrence H. Mirel, 1979-1980 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Miss Utility Bill 3 - 240, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Museum of the City of Washington, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Carolyn Nicholas, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Oath and Affirmation, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Official Requests of the United States list of Names, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Parking, 1981-1988 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Pay Raises - other than education, 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Pennsylvania Avenue, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - People's Counsel Comments on Proposed Rules August 1982 1 of 2 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - People's Counsel Comments on Proposed Rules August 1982 2 of 2 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Phosphate Soaps to Detergents, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Police Outside Bill Employment 4-143, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Police Pay Amendment, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Police Surveillance Bills (old and new), 1977-1981 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Police Retirement, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Public Hearings on the Non Criminal Police Surveillance Act 7/9/76, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Police Records Act (Bill 1-362), 1976 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Political Surveillance, 1975-1976 (Box 34, Folder 5)